ここにいる 全ての兵を率いて出撃し 私の餌を
Don't underestimate the human race, Meruem.
あの　栄養価の高い生物を 捕らえて来るがよい ハッ！
Meruem... That is your name.
おい　何だ？　ありゃ…。 えっ？ うわ！　化け物だ　化け物！ うわ！
Hostility x And x Determination
うわ！ うわ！
The bomb was both low-budget and compact, while also proving surprisingly lethal.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
With the right technology, it was possible to quickly mass
produce these bombs.
あ…。 うっ…　えっ？
Due to the shape of the smoke cloud, it was called the Miniature Rose,
or the poor man's rose, and was popular with small dictatorships.
気に入った場所が見つかるまで 移動を繰り返す。 その間　徐々に兵隊アリを増やし 自らに奉仕する軍団を つくり上げる。
In more than 250 countries and regions of the world, ten times as many roses had bloomed, consuming 5.12 million human lives.
そんな情報や噂は どこからも出てないわ。 やっぱり 取り越し苦労じゃないのかな？ そうそう。 腕　発見当日の 海流データを出してくれ。
After terrorists used the bomb in the
center of an adversarial nation's capital, taking more than 110,000 lives, an international treaty was signed that
banned the bomb's production.
さらに　１０日前に戻してくれ。
However, over eighty percent of the
world's countries rejected the proposal
その１０日間で　発見地点まで 腕を運べる可能性のある 海流域をピックアップ。 どういうこと？
to discard and ban the use of
roses they had already produced, meaning that hundreds of thousands of seeds
本体と腕が切り落とされたのは 本体が　どこかの島に 打ち上げられた後かもしれない。
still wait silently in many countries
for their chance to bloom.
ミテネ連邦も 可能性に入るってことだな。 ミテネ連邦。 あっ ＮＧＬの自治区があるとこね。
When Netero decided to use his last resort, could this thought have crossed his mind?
ああ　東ゴルトーも　この島にある。
Now, there is no way to find out.
自然の中で生活しようって連中が 建てた国。
The two immediately understood
通信手段は　主に手紙 交通手段は　主に馬。
what the distant cloud of smoke and
resulting vibration in the air signified.
８７年には　潜入取材を試みた テレビクルー３名が捕まって １人が処刑　２人は現在も拘留中。
At the same time, Pouf's clone found itself looking Knuckle in the eye.
残りは支援ボランティア。 もしも　その国に　キメラアントの 本体が流れ着いていたら
After his experience with Youpi, Knuckle hoped to reach a
similar understanding with Pouf.
ＮＧＬの人達は　どうすると思う？ 恐らく　何もしない。
But his faint hopes were quickly shattered.
あの腕の持ち主が 本当にキメラアントの女王なら すでに　巣の建設を始めていても おかしくない。
If the King waves his baton, the soldiers will become demons if necessary.
勝負？ ああ。
Pouf's main body must have learned
that something happened to the King.
俺とお前 どっちが大量の人間を 女王様に持って来られるか 勝負しようじゃねえか。
That led to the transformation of the clone's
face, revealing the Ants' true nature.
フッ。 んっ？　逃げんのか？
Did the chairman defeat the King?
おい　勝負しろ！ 「しろ」だ？
No, it doesn't matter either way...
俺に命じてるのか？ なぜ俺が　お前ごときの 命令に従わねばならん。 俺に命じることができるのは 女王様だけだ。
In Pouf's face, Knuckle had seen a barrier
that could not be overcome.
俺様の軍団は精鋭ぞろいだからな。 この城の　どの師団にも 負けるわけねえ。
It's destroyed!
おうおう　そうだ！ どうせなら　お前だけじゃなく
Is everyone okay?
よし！　じゃあ決まりだ。
This is brutal...
だが　俺は　餌の質にも　こだわる。 女王様には より栄養価の高い人間を
It only took them thirty minutes
to wreck the whole place.
生真面目だったのであろう。
That was close...
あっ…。
But I'm glad to see you. You returned to us.
ちょっと　あんた！　休んでなきゃ ダメだって言ったろ！
Then, as planned, I'll take you to Peijing by car.
私　連れ戻して来る。 よしな　無駄だよ。
No, she wants to stay.
でも　こう　毎日毎日　森に行って
Well, she'll certainly be useful in a fight.
朝から晩まで捜し歩いてたら…。 そうだよ　あの人のほうが
In terms of raw offensive power,
she has me beat...
倒れちまうよ。
Probably.
それでも 捜さずにいられないんだよ。
To be honest, I want to go to Gon at once.
それが親ってもんさ。
However...
もう　何日になる？
I'll wait.
クルトくんとレイナちゃんが いなくなってから。
I'll respect his wishes...
まるで　神隠しだよね。
His wishes?
アハハ…！ あっ！
He's decided to fight Pitou by himself.
あっ！　大っきな虫。
I'll wait right here for one hour.
えっ？
And once he's made up his mind,
that's it. He won't budge.
ここは　まだ手つかずのようだな。
In return, he performs his best when circumstances are as expected.
あ!!
B-But what if...
うわっ　うわ！
So that's why they're staying behind.
わっ…　あ！ お母さん！ きっと　あいつらだよ！
Even if Gon uses all the power he currently has, he still won't be able to beat Pitou.
あんたの子供達も きっと　あの化け物に 連れ去られたんだよ！ えっ！
In fact, even if the three of us join him, they're aware that we're still no match for Pitou.
よしよし　これだけ集めれば 女王様も　さぞお喜びに…。
We're also looking for Knuckle and the others. Want to come? Absolutely.
あぁ。
Okay, let's go.
な…　何が!? 虫けらは　早めに駆除しろ
We separated the King and the Royal Guard
それがジャイロの命令だ。
to let the chairman defeat the King.
ジャイロ？　何のことだ？ 俺達の王の名前だ！
As Knov-san said, we've completed
the mission we were assigned.
クソっ。
Do we stop or keep going?
取れたわよ ミテネ連邦までのチケット。
I am
とはいえ　ＮＧＬに入るには
going to keep fighting them.
まず　隣のロカリオ共和国まで 飛行船で行って
I've already laid down my life here more than once.
そこから 陸路で行くしかないけどね。 クロい噂の国には　ひとクロう なんてね　ヤハハハ…！
Even if we can't reach an understanding, I won't give up until I'm content with the outcome.
ああ　ＮＧＬの秘密を探りに 潜入して捕まったんなら
You're finished.
処刑されたんだろうと 思っていたんだが…。 その雑誌記者が ひそかに隠し持っていた
Why did he say that?
通信機から発せられた 最後の音声が
There's still time left...
傍受されてたんだ それを聞かせてもらったら…。
Did he notice that my surgery was done?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ばっ　化け物が… 大きな虫が…！
I made sure to hide my progress from him.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ] 大きな虫。 うん　どう思う？ うん
But if I showed any sign of
relaxing after finishing it, and he noticed that...
それだけじゃ よく分からないけど…
I must kill him.
フッ。
No matter the cost!
幻獣ハンターとしては
I must kill him...
この目で確かめないわけには いかないよな。
For the King's sake!
早速　チケットを ３人分　用意するぜ。
Did he notice my bloodlust then?
４人分よ あっ…。
Stand up.
調査に入る前に　捕まっちゃう。
We move to Peijing now.
だからこそ いざという時のために私が いいえ この子達が必要だと思うの。
Running is faster for us.
なるほど　確かに便利だな。
What happened to me? I would like to—
今さらだが　確かめておきたい。 本当に一緒に来るか？
Am I interrupting something?
もちろん。 ホント　今さらって感じ。 ＮＧＬ国内がどんな状況なのかは 全く分からない。
U-Um, I don't understand what's going on...
巨大なキメラアントが すでに　大量に発生し
I understand. Let's go.
万が一　そうした場面に 遭遇した時には 俺は　彼らを助けることを優先し
Pitou was close enough to take
off his head with one arm.
お前達まで 手が回らないかもしれない。
But Pitou couldn't move.
自分の身は　自分で守る それが連れて行く条件だ。
After seeing how sharp Gon's senses were, Pitou's instincts said to obey.
うん　分かった。 大丈夫。
I can't make a move now...
逆に　もし俺が 危険な状況に陥った時には 構わず逃げろ。
My chance will come. There'll be many, on our way to Peijing.
いいな？
But I must get Komugi to the King!
なかなか大量だわな。
If there's an escape attempt,
I can track Pitou down.
まぁ　でも俺様の軍団の半分も 捕れてねえわな。
And if Pitou tries to fight back,
APR will protect you.
フン　まぁ　いい それより　聞いたか？
Thank you, Knuckle.
あのカメジジイが 人間の反撃に遭ったそうだ。
But it's okay.
反撃？ ふん…　それは恐らく
I trust Pitou...
銃というものだな。 「銃」？ 簡単にいえば 弾丸と呼ばれる金属の弾を
So until Pitou and I have met with Kite, keep an eye on her.
火薬の爆発力によって 撃ち出す筒。 人間が最もよく使う 武器の一つだ。
A-Are you talking about me?
人間も軍隊を持っているのか？ 軍隊？
Is he going to use Komugi... As a hostage?!
そう　あれは　まさしく軍隊。 強い権限を持つ指揮官によって
Once Pitou turns Kite back, we'll let her go.
率いられた軍隊に相違ない。 そうじゃ　もう一つ尋ねたい。
I'm sure you're also willing to trust me, right?
奴らが言った　「名前」とは何じゃ？
Pitou?
ただ泣き叫んで 逃げ回るだけじゃないのが。
You sure about this, Killua?
別に　驚きはしない。
You aren't going with Gon?
俺とお前の性格が違うように
We were...
人間にも さまざまな個性があって当然だ。
No, Killua was prepared to die with Gon.
何しろ　俺達も その血を引いてるんだからな。
But Gon didn't want him to come!
師団長ども　集まれ！
It's okay.
And I feel better after hearing what he's doing.
女王様のお呼びだ。
You mean the hostage?
師団長ども　集まれ！ 女王様からの信号って 頭　痛くならないか？
Yeah. The real danger would be if I went along, and Pitou managed to capture me.
ああ　耳鳴りも キンってするしね。
Then Pitou would have the option
to exchange hostages.
女王様も　私達みたく 話せたらいいのにね。
Seriously... What have they been through for
their minds to work this way?
これより私は 王を産む準備に専念する
Now that I've seen Gon with these eyes, I'll know immediately if something happens.
ついては　一日５０体 人間を私に届けよ
Besides, Pitou won't abandon her.
ハッ！
Which means that Gon is safe.
女王様 よろしいでしょうか？ 許す　話せ 人間には 我々と同じ兵隊がおり
I can't understand what's going on.
多様な武器を持ち　身を守ります
Where is the Supreme Leader? Who are these people?
私どもに名前を持つ許しを 頂けませぬか？ 「名前」とは何だ？ 記号のようなものでございます
The heat of the explosion had
melted the rock into magma, leaving a scene resembling the
mouth of an active volcano, producing a perpetual cloud of black smoke
まぁ　よい　好きにせい
that prevented the living from entering.
自己主張し 名前などというものを欲しがり
Pouf!
種のために競うように 功を成そうとする反面 かたくなに　個を重んじる
I'll search inside, so I need you to
search the surrounding area. It's possible that the explosion
sent the King flying.
それを面白いと思う私もまた 変わり者か
I was wrong...
恐らく　薄くではあるが 私にも人間の血が 混じっているのかもしれぬ
We will kill them all, with the King at our side. None will be spared!
ああ　何か　有無を言わせぬ 感じだったよな。 うん。 だから２人とも 結局　返事できなかったけど
Your Majesty!
…ったく　真剣な顔して言うから もっと深いこと 言うのかと思ったら
Youpi's roar had an ominous tone.
結局　いつものゴンじゃん。 え　これでも悩んだんだよ。 頭の中で いろんなシミュレーションしたりして。 いくら考えたって　ゴンはゴン。
Before he could even see the truth for himself, tears were already streaming down Pouf's face.
誰かを見捨てて 「逃げろ」と言われたって できるわきゃねえよな。
Your Majesty!
うん　何か　悩むだけ無駄って 言われてるみたいだけど。